<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peering Policy</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Peering Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 13:45:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gsma Cnic Peering</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/gsma-cnic-peering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 11:38:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/gsma-cnic-peering/</guid>
      <description>Peering Policy Introduction Welcome to our peering policy page. This document outlines the guidelines and requirements for establishing peering connections with our network.
Guidelines Eligibility: Peering requests are evaluated based on specific criteria. Technical Requirements: Peering partners must meet certain technical requirements. Routing Policies: Our routing policies and procedures are outlined here. Contact Information: Contact details for peering inquiries. CentralNic Registry GRX Bilateral Peering Policy 1. Definitions Terms used in this Peering Policy that are not defined below or in the Agreement are defined in the context in which they are used and have the meanings there stated, and:</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;peering-policy&#34;&gt;Peering Policy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our peering policy page. This document outlines the guidelines and requirements for establishing peering connections with our network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;guidelines&#34;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eligibility:&lt;/strong&gt; Peering requests are evaluated based on specific criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt; Peering partners must meet certain technical requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Routing Policies:&lt;/strong&gt; Our routing policies and procedures are outlined here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Information:&lt;/strong&gt; Contact details for peering inquiries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralnic-registry-grx-bilateral-peering-policy&#34;&gt;CentralNic Registry GRX Bilateral Peering Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-definitions&#34;&gt;1. Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terms used in this Peering Policy that are not defined below or in the Agreement are defined in the context in which they are used and have the meanings there stated, and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous System&lt;/strong&gt;: A connected group of one or more IP prefixes run by one or more network operators, which has a single and clearly defined routing policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Border Gateway Protocol (BGP)&lt;/strong&gt;: Standard(s) for inter-Autonomous System routing protocol(s) as recommended now or in the future by the Internet Engineering Task Force (“IETF”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explicit Route&lt;/strong&gt;: A route that covers only a strict, limited subset of all possible destinations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interconnection Point&lt;/strong&gt;: Any interconnection point, public or private, at which the parties agree to connect their respective Networks under this Policy. A description of all Interconnection Points is set forth on Schedule 1 attached hereto and incorporated by this reference, and Schedule 1 shall be amended in writing only by mutual agreement of the parties in the event of any changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Protocol (IP)&lt;/strong&gt;: Networking protocols and procedures, used to provide communication across interconnected networks, that meet the definition of Internet Standards as agreed upon by the Network Working Group of the Internet Architecture Board (“IAB”) and the IETF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Service Provider (ISP)&lt;/strong&gt;: A seller of public Internet access and connectivity services operating a Network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt;: A communications network running IP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CentralNic&lt;/strong&gt;: CentralNic, a limited liability company with a principal place of business at Saddlers House, 44 Gutter Ln, London EC2V 6BR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Route of Last Resort (default route)&lt;/strong&gt;: A route directing traffic for which no explicit route exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Party&lt;/strong&gt;: Any party other than Customer or CentralNic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Party Transit Services&lt;/strong&gt;: The use of an ISP’s Network to transport traffic between or among two or more destinations, where neither of those destinations is a customer of that ISP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;peering-policy-1&#34;&gt;Peering Policy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-introduction&#34;&gt;2. Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Peering Policy describes and defines the minimum criteria that CentralNic has established for providing the interconnection between the CentralNic Networks and other Internet Networks in the various regions of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-connectivity-and-network-peering-requirements&#34;&gt;3. Connectivity and Network Peering Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;31-exchange-of-ip-traffic&#34;&gt;3.1 Exchange of IP Traffic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parties agree to exchange IP traffic using BGP between their respective Networks at Interconnection Points that shall have been agreed upon by the parties in writing (including, without limitation, by email).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;32-bgp-version-and-connectivity&#34;&gt;3.2 BGP Version and Connectivity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parties agree to maintain a current BGP version. Each party shall provide, at its own expense, a connection from its Network to the Interconnection Points hereunder. Each party shall bear the cost of the termination equipment at the end of its connection to the Interconnection Points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;33-traffic-restrictions&#34;&gt;3.3 Traffic Restrictions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each party agrees not to restrict traffic flowing through the Interconnection Points to and from the other party based on the subject matter of the traffic, unless required to do so by an appropriate regulation, order, or similar action of a court, regulatory or governmental agency of competent jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;34-prohibition-of-third-party-transit-services&#34;&gt;3.4 Prohibition of Third Party Transit Services&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of the other party’s Network for Third Party Transit Services (the use of one party’s network to transport traffic between or among two or more destinations, where neither of those destinations is a customer of that party) is strictly prohibited under this Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;35-minimum-interconnection-points&#34;&gt;3.5 Minimum Interconnection Points&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interconnection at a minimum of two (2) diverse peering points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;36-routing-configuration&#34;&gt;3.6 Routing Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentralNic reserves the right to modify the routing configuration in coordination with the Peer as necessary in order to improve routing between the CentralNic and Peer networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;technical-and-operational-requirements&#34;&gt;Technical and Operational Requirements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;41-cooperation-and-operational-standards&#34;&gt;4.1 Cooperation and Operational Standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parties agree to cooperate and to use all reasonable efforts to create and adopt mutually agreeable performance and operational standards and procedures in order to facilitate the provision of high-quality, cost-effective services utilizing each party’s Network and the Interconnection Point(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;42-network-architecture-and-redundancy&#34;&gt;4.2 Network Architecture and Redundancy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each party represents to the other that the Interconnection Point(s) are connected as part of an internal Network architecture. Peer must operate a fully redundant network capable of handling a single-node outage in each network without significantly affecting the traffic being exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;43-network-operations-center-noc&#34;&gt;4.3 Network Operations Center (NOC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each party shall maintain a fully staffed network operations center (“NOC”) that operates on a 24 hours/day and 7-days/week basis. The Parties shall exchange up-to-date contact information for their respective NOCs and shall continue to keep such information updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;44-confidentiality-and-information-disclosure&#34;&gt;4.4 Confidentiality and Information Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peering does not include the right to disclose or obtain information related to the NeuStar Network topology or configuration to a third party outside the scope of troubleshooting within the peer’s organization or equipment vendor(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;routing-requirements&#34;&gt;Routing Requirements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;51-as-numbers-and-ip-addresses&#34;&gt;5.1 AS Numbers and IP Addresses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Peers must use globally unique AS Numbers and IP Addresses (including the Peer ID).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;52-internet-routing-registry&#34;&gt;5.2 Internet Routing Registry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each party should register the routes, routing domains, and routing policies of its public Internet subscribers in a public Internet Routing Registry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;53-packet-delay&#34;&gt;5.3 Packet Delay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each party shall use their reasonable efforts to achieve a minimum end-to-end one-way packet delay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;54-multi-exit-discriminator-med-attributes&#34;&gt;5.4 Multi-Exit Discriminator (MED) Attributes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each party shall announce routes using multi-exit discriminator (“MED”) attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;55-third-party-routes&#34;&gt;5.5 Third Party Routes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neither party shall send Third Party routes, and necessary precautions should be taken to prevent leaking transit routes to each other. If a party detects Third Party routes without notice to the other party, it shall have the right to block such routes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;56-consistent-routing&#34;&gt;5.6 Consistent Routing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The parties shall maintain a consistent routing announcement, presenting the same Autonomous System number as well as advertise consistent prefixes at all mutual Interconnection Point(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;57-advertise-necessary-network-prefixes&#34;&gt;5.7 Advertise Necessary Network Prefixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Peer shall only advertise necessary network prefixes that need to access CentralNic services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;58-packet-filters-and-bad-traffic&#34;&gt;5.8 Packet Filters and Bad Traffic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CentralNic reserves the right to apply packet filters which prevent bad traffic including the injection of spoofed packets, malicious traffic, misconfiguration, abuse of network capacity. CentralNic reserves the right to temporarily de-peer as a result of receiving bad traffic from a peer which results in a degradation in performance to other peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;59-md5-digest-authentication&#34;&gt;5.9 MD5 Digest Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Peers must use MD5 digest to authenticate BGP4 sessions and specify individually unique strings for each and every session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;510-route-of-last-resort&#34;&gt;5.10 Route of Last Resort&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neither party shall establish a Route of Last Resort (default route) directed toward the other party’s Network. Instead, the parties will fully exchange explicit routes comprising public Internet service destinations of entities whose traffic either party is obligated contractually to carry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;511-soft-reconfiguration&#34;&gt;5.11 Soft Reconfiguration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All peers must support soft reconfiguration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-customer-relations-and-administration&#34;&gt;6. Customer Relations and Administration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;61-communication-with-customers&#34;&gt;6.1 Communication with Customers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each party shall be responsible for communicating with its own customers with respect to its Network. However, nothing in this Section shall be interpreted as limiting in any way the ability of either party to engage in confidential discussions with customers of the other party hereto or as requiring notification thereof to the other party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;62-traffic-screening&#34;&gt;6.2 Traffic Screening&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each party shall be responsible to screen the traffic of its own customers not desiring public Internet access from distribution across the Interconnection Point(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;63-pricing-and-charges&#34;&gt;6.3 Pricing and Charges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each party shall independently establish the charges to its own customers for the services provided in connection with this Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-customer-transmitted-data&#34;&gt;7. Customer Transmitted Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;71-data-monitoring&#34;&gt;7.1 Data Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except for data required for traffic analysis and traffic control being examined in order for the parties to operate their respective Network, neither party shall monitor the content of any data or other traffic of the other party, which passes through the Interconnection Point(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;72-network-modification&#34;&gt;7.2 Network Modification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither party shall modify its Network infrastructure or Interconnect Point(s) in any way to examine any data of the other party, unless required to do so by an appropriate regulation, order, or similar action of a court, regulatory or governmental agency of competent jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;73-data-sharing-with-third-parties&#34;&gt;7.3 Data Sharing with Third Parties&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise agreed between the parties in writing, or upon reasonable written notice and in order to comply with an appropriate regulation, order or similar action of a court, regulatory or governmental agency of competent jurisdiction, neither party shall provide to Third Parties any statistical information derived from data or other traffic of the other party itemized by service provider, by company, or by IP address; provided, however, that each party may provide any of its customers with the customer’s own statistical data, and each party may use such data for projecting future capacity needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-limitation-on-services&#34;&gt;8. Limitation on Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Policy shall apply only to IP traffic passing between the parties’ respective Networks. Virtual private data network services and services involving protocols other than the Internet protocols are not covered by this Policy. Neither party shall be entitled or required to carry traffic hereunder if doing so would conflict with any condition imposed by an agreement between the other party and any third party with whom the other party connects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-regulatory-approval&#34;&gt;9. Regulatory Approval.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that this Policy, or any of the terms hereof, becomes subject to regulatory approval by any regulatory authority in any jurisdiction including any local, state or federal agencies, the parties shall cooperate, to the extent reasonable and lawful, in providing such information as is necessary to complete any required filing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;appendix-1-technical-data&#34;&gt;APPENDIX 1: Technical Data&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Peering Policy of both parties is dependent on (a) the following parameters in respect of CentralNic and (b) the parameters set out in the GSMA Root DNS Service Agreement in respect of Customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-contact-details&#34;&gt;Technical Contact details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address: Saddlers House, 44 Gutter Ln, London EC2V 6BR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone: 020 3388 0600&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (General):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (Peering):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;asn&#34;&gt;ASN:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11111&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tsig&#34;&gt;TSIG:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Required for XFR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pops&#34;&gt;PoP&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMS_1:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Netherlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMS_2:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Netherlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-3&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-4&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SGX:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Singapore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-5&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-6&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IAD:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Location: Ashburn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NS-8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRX IP: 1.1.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks: 2.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



  &lt;div class=&#34;collapsable-code&#34;&gt;
    &lt;input id=&#34;1&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked /&gt;
    &lt;label for=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&#34;collapsable-code__language&#34;&gt;css&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&#34;collapsable-code__title&#34;&gt;Really cool snippet&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&#34;collapsable-code__toggle&#34; data-label-expand=&#34;Show&#34; data-label-collapse=&#34;Hide&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&#34;language-css&#34; &gt;&lt;code&gt;
test
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 13:45:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>## About page</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;## About page&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
